# Joseph Alexander Guidry

Department of Astronomy, Boston University, 725 Commonwealth Avenue, Boston, MA, 02215 **☑** jaguidry [at] bu [dot] edu

% website 📗 🖸 github 📗 🕩 ORCiD

#### SUMMARY.

I am a Ph.D. student worker and NSF Graduate Resarch Fellow at the Institute for Astrophysical Research in the Department of Astronomy at Boston University (Aug. 2021 – present). I work in the BU White Dwarf Group under the supervision of Prof. JJ Hermes.

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS \_

WHITE DWARF STARS remnant planetary systems | pulsating white dwarfs | magnetic white dwarfs

VARIABLE STARS time-domain surveys | time-series astronomy | transiting systems

**SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT** open source software | data reduction and processing | time-series analysis

#### **EDUCATION**

**BOSTON UNIVERSITY** August 2021 - present

PhD Student, Department of Astronomy

M.A. Astronomy expected 2024

**UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN** 

August 2017 - May 2021 B.S. Astronomy (with Honors)

**B.S. Physics** 

Cumulative GPA: 3.76/4.00

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

An ADS guery of my publications can be accessed here.

#### FIRST-AUTHORED REFEREED PUBLICATIONS

1. **Guidry, J. A.**, Vanderbosch, Z. P., Hermes, J. J., et al. 2021, *ApJ*, 912, 125. I Spy Transits and Pulsations: Empirical Variability in White Dwarfs Using Gaia and the Zwicky Transient Facility.

#### REFEREED PUBLICATIONS AS CONTRIBUTING AUTHOR

- 1. Farihi, J., Hermes, J. J., Marsh, T. R., ..., Guidry, J. A. (author 6/14), et al. 2022, MNRAS, 511, 1647. Relentless and complex transits from a planetesimal debris disc.
- 2. Vanderbosch, Z. P., Rappaport, S., Guidry, J. A., et al. 2021, ApJ, 917, 41. Recurring Planetary Debris Transits and Circumstellar Gas around White Dwarf ZTF 10328-1219.
- 3. Kupfer, T., Prince, T. A., van Roestel, J., ..., Guidry, J. A. (author 18/21), et al. 2021, MNRAS, 505, 1254. Year 1 of the ZTF high-cadence Galactic plane survey: strategy, goals, and early results on new single-mode hot subdwarf B-star pulsators.

#### **CONFERENCE ABSTRACTS**

- 1. Extreme Solar Systems V: Guidry, J., Hermes, J. J., Vanderbosch, Z. P. 2024, Poster 612.01. Transiting Planetary Debris around White Dwarfs: New Discoveries and Emerging Dichotomies
- 2. 237th American Astronomical Society Meeting: **Guidry, J. A.**, Vanderbosch, Z. P., Hermes, J. J., et al. 2021, AAS. I Spy Variability and Transits: Detecting Variable White Dwarfs Using Gaia and Zwicky Transient Facility **Photometry Variability Metrics**

#### **OUTREACH PUBLICATIONS**

1. Astrobites Guest Submission: UR: I Spy Transits and Pulsations – Empirical Variability in White Dwarfs Using Gaia and the Zwicky Transient Facility.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **RESEARCH FELLOW**

May 2022 – present | Boston University

• Began tenure of NSF Graduate Research Fellowship August 202.

#### **TEACHING FELLOW**

August 2021 – May 2022 | Boston University

- Taught lab portions AS 102, The Astronomical Universe for non-majors, spring 2022 course at Boston University (instructor Prof. Jane Luu).
- Taught lab portions AS 202, Principles of Astronomy I for majors, fall 2021 course at Boston University (instructor Prof. Paul Withers).

#### FRESHMAN RESEARCH INITIATIVE PEER MENTOR

January 2019 - August 2021 | UT Austin

Peer Mentor in the FRI White Dwarf Stars stream (PIs: Dr. Mike Montgomery, Prof. Don Winget)

• Served as a mentor to the students of the white dwarf FRI stream by assisting them with their weekly labs and advising them on their research projects. I was trained to employed Socratic methods so that the students led their inquiries.

#### **UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH FELLOW**

May 2018 - August 2018; May 2020 - August 2020 | UT Austin

- Summer 2020: worked full-time on Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship awarded by the Department of Astronomy, UT Austin. Advised by Dr. Zach Vanderbosch (then graduate student) and Dr. Mike Montgomery.
- Summer 2018: worked part-time on TIDES/FRI Summer Fellowship awarded by the TIDES office at UT Austin. Advised by Dr. Mike Montgomery of the FRI White Dwarf Stars stream.

#### AWARDS AND FELLOWSHIPS \_\_\_\_\_

2022	NSF Graduate Research Fellowship Program	National Science Foundation
2021	George H. Mitchell Award (STEM Category)	College of Natural Sciences, UT Austin
2021	Graduate with Distinction in Research	College of Natural Sciences, UT Austin
2021	Graduate with Distinction in Diversity, Equity, & Inclusion	College of Natural Sciences, UT Austin
2020	Outstanding Senior Award	Department of Astronomy, UT Austin
2020	Abel Family Scholarship in Physics	Department of Physics, UT Austin
2020	NSC Endowed Service Scholarship	Natural Sciences Council, UT Austin
2020	Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship	J. W. Cox Endowment for the Advanced
		Studies in Astronomy, UT Austin
2019	Melvin J. Rieger Scholarship Fund in Physics	Department of Physics, UT Austin
2019	C. M. & J. C. Thompson Scholarship in Physics	Department of Physics, UT Austin
2019	CNS Second Year Excellence Award	College of Natural Sciences, UT Austin
2018	Dr. H. Franklyn Alexander Endowed Scholarship	College of Natural Sciences, UT Austin
2018	TIDES FRI Summer Research Fellowship	Texas Institute for Discovery Education
		in Science, UT Austin

## CONFERENCE AND WORKSHOP PARTICIPATION \_

#### **CONTRIBUTED TALKS**

- ZTF 5<sup>th</sup> Science Meeting, The Nascent Class of White Dwarfs Showing Transits from Exoplanetary Debris, Caltech, October 2023
- KITP Conference: White Dwarfs from Physics to Astrophysics, Characterizing the Orbital Periods of Transiting Planetary Debris around White Dwarfs, KITP-University of California, Santa Barbara, November 2022
- EUROWD22: 22nd European Workshop on White Dwarfs, Characterizing the Orbital Periods of Transiting Planetary Debris around White Dwarfs, University of Tübingen, August 2022

#### RESEARCH POSTERS PRESENTED

- 1. Frank N. Bash Symposium, Searching for Color Changes During Outburst, October 2019, Austin, TX
- TASC5/KASC12, Searching for Color Changes During Outburst, July 2019, Cambridge, MA

#### **WORKSHOPS ATTENDED**

- ZTF Summer School, August 2021
- Code/Astro 2021, June 2021

#### **OTHER PRESENTATIONS**

#### **INVITED TALKS**

- Institute for Theory and Computation Luncheon, Ancient Planetesimals Colliding around White Dwarfs, Center for Astrophysics, Harvard University, April 2023
- Exoplanet Pizza Lunch, Characterizing the Orbital Periods of Transiting Planetary Debris around White Dwarfs, Center for Astrophysics, Harvard University, September 2022

#### **OUTREACH TALKS**

- 1. North Shore Amateur Astronomy Club, Can the oldest stars in the Galaxy reveal the fate of the Solar System?, September 2023, Boxford, MA
- 2. BU Astronomical Society, Probing the Orbital Dynamics of Remnant Planetary Systems Using Autocorrelation, February 2022, Boston University

#### **OBSERVING EXPERIENCE**

PERKINS TELESCOPE OBSERVATORY

• Observed 33 nights as PI at Boston University's Perkins Telescope Observatory, Flagstaff, AZ over November 2021-present.

#### LOWELL DISCOVERY TELESCOPE

• Observed 2 nights as PI on the Lowell Discovery Telescope, Happy Jack, AZ over January 2024–present.

#### **McDonald Observatory**

 Observed 8 nights as PI at McDonald Observatory's Otto Struve Telescope, Fort Davis, TX over June 2024-present.

#### OTHER SERVICE

#### **BOSTON UNIVERSITY GRADUATE WORKERS UNION (BUGWU)**

- 1. Bargaining Team Member, June 2023-present
- 2. Union Representative for the Astronomy Department, August 2022–present

#### SKILLS

Experienced: Python | Familiar: IRAF | Learning: Julia PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

**SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT** Git | PyPI

Jupyter | Matplotplib | Numpy | Pandas | Astropy | Photutils FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES

LANGUAGES Native: English Beginner: French

### REFERENCES \_

Boston University (jjhermes@bu.edu) Prof. JJ Hermes California Institute of Technology (zvanderb@caltech.edu) Dr. Zachary Vanderbosch Dr. Mike Montgomery The University of Texas at Austin (mikemon@astro.as.utexas.edu)